const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 70-year-old male patient presents to the clinic with complaints of feeling something sticking in his throat, difficulty in swallowing, and weight loss. He also gives a history of regurgitating undigested food 4 to 5 hours after consumption. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Barret's esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma of the pyriform fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Achalasia","bool":false},{"option":"Zenker's diverticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A young woman comes to the clinic with the complaint of intermittent episodes of vertigo on turning her head to the left. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Meniere disease","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Psychogenic vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Benign paroxysmal positional vertigo","bool":true},{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 20-year-old male reports to the clinic after a flight with complaints of bilateral severe earache, deafness, and tinnitus. Otoscopy reveals bubbles in the middle ear across a retracted eardrum. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aero-otitis media","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic secretory otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media with effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Serous otitis media","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Noise is an undesirable and unwanted vibration of sound that can cause damage to humans both physically and mentally. The intensity of sound is measured in decibels (dB). Which of the following is the daily acceptable limit of noise that the human ear can tolerate without any substantial damage to hearing?","answers":[{"option":"95 dB","bool":false},{"option":"85 dB","bool":true},{"option":"65 dB","bool":false},{"option":"45 dB","bool":false},{"option":"75 dB","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A mother brings in her 4-year-old boy to the clinic with complaints of severe right-sided earache, high-grade fever, and mild hearing impairment. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Otomycosis","bool":false},{"option":"Boil ear","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Serous otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Acute otitis media","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 17-year-old male presents to the emergency department with the complaint of bleeding from the nose after suffering a trauma. Which of the following is the most common site of epistaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral wall of nose","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroinferior part of nasal septum","bool":true},{"option":"Caudal end of nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior part of nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Roof of nasal cavity","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 21-year-old female presents to the otorhinolaryngology outpatient department with the complaint of painless and progressive hearing loss. Her hearing is better in noisy surroundings. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Adhesive otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Acute otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Acute mastoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Meniere's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Otospongiosis","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 75-year-old lady comes to the clinic with the complaint of decreased hearing bilaterally. Her blood pressure is 145/98 mmHg and her ear examination is unremarkable. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tympanosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrovascular accident","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory neural deafness","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 4-year-old girl is brought into the clinic by her mother with the complaint of bilateral hearing loss for the last 6 months. She has also been snoring at night. Otoscopy reveals fluid level with air bubbles in both ears along with dull, bluish, and retracted tympanic membranes. What is the most likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acute suppurative otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Glue ear (otitis media with effusion)","bool":true},{"option":"Malignant otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Adhesive otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Safe type chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Tuning fork tests were conducted on a 26-year-old woman. Rinne's test revealed that bone conduction was greater than air conduction in both of her ears. Weber's test was centralized and Schwabach's test was equal to that of the examiner in both ears. Which of the following is the most likely explanation for these findings?","answers":[{"option":"Noised induced deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Meniere disease","bool":false},{"option":"Dislocation of ossicles","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthitis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"An 18-year-old male presents to the clinic with a diffuse swelling in the submandibular region, fever, ptyalism, and difficulty in chewing. He also gives a history of toothache. On examination, the swelling is diffuse, firm, and brawny with raised floor of the mouth. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infectious mononucleosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Ludwig angina","bool":true},{"option":"Ranula","bool":false},{"option":"Sialadenitis","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 28-year-old female visits the outpatient department with complaints of restricted mouth opening, burning of the mouth, and intolerance to spicy food. She is habitual of chewing betel nuts for the last 12 years. Which premalignant condition is most likely to be present in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral submucous fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Leukoerythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Erythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Lichen planus","bool":false},{"option":"Leukoplakia","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 24-year-old male visits the clinic with a complaint of a swelling in the floor of the oral cavity that ruptures and reappears on and off for the last 2 years. Oral examination reveals a transparent globular cystic swelling in the floor of the mouth. What is the most likely clinical diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Dermoid","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor of oral cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ranula","bool":true},{"option":"Sebaceous cyst","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 34-year-old patient presents to the outpatient clinic with complaints of sudden onset vertigo, tinnitus, and fluctuating hearing loss. This attack was preceded by a sensation of fullness in the affected ear. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Meniere disease","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthitis","bool":false},{"option":"Benign paroxymal positional vertigo","bool":false},{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 45-year-old malnourished lady is having difficulty swallowing for the past 6 months. Oral cavity examination revealed smooth tongue and fissures at both angles of the mouth. Which of these diagnostic tests are required in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Fiber-optic direct laryngoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Upper gastrointestinal endoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Neck ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray barium swallow","bool":true},{"option":"CT scan/MRI neck","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 7-year-old child has undergone a tonsillectomy. Just after a few hours of surgery in the ward. He develops bleeding from the operative site. What is the type of hemorrhage?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Primary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Peroperative hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Reactionary hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Perioperative hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A patient came with complaints of dyspnea in the emergency room. The doctor planned a high tracheostomy for his management. Which of the following is the indication of high tracheostomy?","answers":[{"option":"Carcinoma of larynx","bool":true},{"option":"Acute epiglottitis","bool":false},{"option":"Elective tracheostomy","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body throat","bool":false},{"option":"Ludwig's angina","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"What is the most common congenital neck cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Retention cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Brancial cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Sebaceous cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroglossal duct cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Dermoid cyst","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Which one of the following became the first international research trial on ethics that involves human subjects?","answers":[{"option":"Declaration of Geneva","bool":false},{"option":"Nuremberg code","bool":true},{"option":"Helsinki declaration","bool":false},{"option":"Belmont report","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocratic oath","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Which of the following is the first complete historic documentation regarding the ethical practice of a medical doctor?","answers":[{"option":"Hippocratic oath","bool":true},{"option":"Nuremberg code","bool":false},{"option":"Declaration of Geneva","bool":false},{"option":"Helsinki declaration","bool":false},{"option":"Belmont report","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"The professor of Medicine was reviewing the proformas constructed by the resident trainee. The proforma contained a consent form, patients’ socio-demographics such as name, age, gender, address, and clinical details on the severity of disease, antibiotics used, and the clinical outcome of the patient. The professor is also the principal investigator of this research titled “Effectiveness of antibiotics in the treatment of gastrointestinal infections”. In the given scenario, which research ethics principle is at risk of violation?","answers":[{"option":"Patient autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Quality of care","bool":false},{"option":"Informed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Patient confidentiality","bool":true},{"option":"Standard of care","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A researcher assessed the effect of blood glucose levels on the running capacity of students in a marathon race. He made two groups and provided sugar-sweetened beverages to group A and nothing was provided to group B. The researcher measured and compared the running speed of the participants in group A and group B. What could be the most appropriate statistical test in this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"F-test","bool":false},{"option":"Independent sample t-test","bool":true},{"option":"Paired sample t-test","bool":false},{"option":"Chi square","bool":false},{"option":"ANOVA","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A senior obstetrician claims that the mean hemoglobin level of pregnant women of Karachi is not more than 11.5 g/dl. To test this claim, a community survey is conducted. What could be the most appropriate statistical test for this purpose?","answers":[{"option":"F-test","bool":false},{"option":"ANOVA","bool":false},{"option":"Paired sample t-test","bool":false},{"option":"Chi square test","bool":false},{"option":"One sample t-test","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A group of final year medical students is collecting online data from adolescents about their pubertal and sexual issues. They intend to use a self-administered questionnaire, which also contains an inventory to assess anxiety and depression in the same sample. Before proceeding with this research study, whom must they obtain permission from?","answers":[{"option":"Head of medicine","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical coordinator","bool":false},{"option":"Medical superintendent","bool":false},{"option":"Ethics committee","bool":true},{"option":"College principal","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A pus swab for culture and sensitivity is sent for a 28-year-old man who is suffering from atticoantral type of chronic suppurative otitis media (CSOM). What is the most common organism causing this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 20-year-old female presents to the outpatient clinic with complaints of pain, redness, and swelling in her right ear for 5 days. She had her ears pierced a week ago. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Auricular hematoma","bool":false},{"option":"Boil","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Keloid","bool":false},{"option":"Perichondritis","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Which of the following is the best investigation for Wegener granulomatosis?","answers":[{"option":"c-ANCA levels","bool":false},{"option":"Histopathology","bool":true},{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography scan","bool":false},{"option":"p-ANCA levels","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Which of the following is a suitable description of ethics?","answers":[{"option":"Something we ought to do","bool":true},{"option":"Something we should do","bool":false},{"option":"Something we must do","bool":false},{"option":"Something we can do","bool":false},{"option":"Something we want to do","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A professor is conducting research on a specific antibiotic. He asks a student to provide information about the patients treated with that specific antibiotic. The information included the name, age, ethnicity, and address of the patients. Which ethical principle will be violated if the student provides the information?","answers":[{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Justice","bool":false},{"option":"Nonmaleficence","bool":false},{"option":"Confidentiality","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 35-year-old female presents with profuse bleeding from the nose and mouth. Anterior nasal packing is done to stop the bleeding but it does not stop the bleeding. What is the next best step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior nasal packing with anterior packing","bool":true},{"option":"Endoscopy to locate the bleeder","bool":false},{"option":"Ligation of maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Endoscopic ligation of external carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ligation of sphenopalatine artery","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 35-year-old factory worker in Karachi, on his general check-up, is worried about noise-induced hearing loss. The physician advises him to limit his daily exposure to noise. According to local guidelines, what is the maximum limit of daily noise exposure which people can tolerate without significant damage to their hearing?","answers":[{"option":"95 dB","bool":false},{"option":"45 dB","bool":false},{"option":"65 dB","bool":false},{"option":"100 dB","bool":false},{"option":"85 dB","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 3-month-old child presents to the clinic with stridor which is aggravated by crying but gets better on lying prone. What is the most appropriate diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Laryngocele","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottitis","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngomalacia","bool":true},{"option":"Laryngo-esophageal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital subglottic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"What is the investigation of choice for suspected nasopharyngeal angiofibroma?","answers":[{"option":"Carotid angiography","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan of the base of the skull","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan of the head with contrast","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 45-year-old male patient presented to the ENT outpatient department with a history of clear fluid coming from the nose. The discharge is continuous, can not be sniffed back and there is a history of head injury 2 weeks back. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Allergic rhinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute sinusitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor rhinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic granulomatous disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid rhinorrhea","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A boy is suffering from acute otitis media. The tympanic membrane is bulging and his symptoms are not improving despite adequate medical treatment. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment option?","answers":[{"option":"Mastoidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Topical lignocaine drops","bool":false},{"option":"Aspiration","bool":false},{"option":"Myringotomy","bool":true},{"option":"Analgesics","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 4-year-old patient underwent esophagoscopy for obstructed meal bolus and 6 hours after surgery the patient developed severe pain in the interscapular region. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Esophageal perforation","bool":true},{"option":"Major vessel injury","bool":false},{"option":"Retained foreign body","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse esophagitis","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 3-year-old child presents to the emergency department with a complaint of high-grade fever, dyspnea, and lethargy. The condition is somewhat relieved by sitting position with bending forward. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acute tonsillitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute peritonsillar abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Acute epiglottitis","bool":true},{"option":"Acute laryngotracheobronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Parapharyngeal abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 40-year-old factory worker presents with a complaint of progressive loss of hearing in both ears for the last three years. His pure tone audiometry is done which reveals sensorineural hearing loss in both ears with a dip in air and bone conduction at 4K. This type of graph is typically seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Meniere’s disease","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Noise trauma","bool":true},{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 58-year-old man with a known comorbidity of diabetes mellitus for the past 10 years presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of developing sudden pain in the right ear with a fever. On examination, there is severe inflammation with small red swelling in the external auditory canal. The tympanic membrane is intact. The patient is most likely suffering from which condition?","answers":[{"option":"Boil ear","bool":true},{"option":"Acute otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the ear","bool":false},{"option":"CSOM with cholesteatoma","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"When there is a need for an emergency airway opening, the cricothyroid membrane should be immediately pierced. Where exactly is the cricothyroid membrane located?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior to cricoid cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Superior to cricoid cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Between 2nd and 3rd tracheal ring","bool":false},{"option":"Superior to thyroid isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior to thyroid cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"An 8-year-old boy was diagnosed as a case of Bezold abscess. What is the location of pus in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall of ear","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid tip","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Petrous apex","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 23-year-old male patient is diagnosed with a case of otitis media with effusion which is not responding to the medical treatment. Which of the following surgical procedures is required in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Tympanotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoidectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanoplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Myringotomy with grommet insertion","bool":true},{"option":"Myringoplasty","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 30-year-old lady who had otosclerosis in both ears got pregnant. What will be the effect of pregnancy on her ear symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Symptoms will remain same","bool":false},{"option":"Some other symptoms will develop","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms will decrease","bool":false},{"option":"Symptoms will increase","bool":true},{"option":"Symptoms will disappear","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"An 18-year-old male patient presents to the emergency department after being slapped by someone on his left ear. On examination, he has perforation in his left ear. Which type of perforation do you expect in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Multiple perforations in pars tensa","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular perforation in pars flaccida","bool":false},{"option":"Posterosuperior marginal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Pin-hole perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Central perforation with irregular margins and tiny clots","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 30-year-old female patient came to the clinic after some insect had gone into her right ear, half an hour back. What solution is used to kill or make an insect unconscious before its removal?","answers":[{"option":"Ketamine drops","bool":false},{"option":"Halothane drops","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine drops","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotic ear drops","bool":false},{"option":"Oil drops","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 7-year-old boy presents with a complaint of bilateral deafness. After evaluation, he is diagnosed with a case of enlarged adenoids. What is the typical type of deafness seen in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Sensorineural","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed","bool":false},{"option":"Functional","bool":false},{"option":"Conductive","bool":true},{"option":"Selective deafness","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Which of the following conditions is often associated with snoring?","answers":[{"option":"Sleep apnea syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Deviated nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac diseases","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 20-year-old male patient underwent tonsillectomy. One week later, the patient presented with bleeding from the mouth with hematemesis. What is the most common cause of secondary hemorrhage after tonsillectomy?","answers":[{"option":"Slippage of ligature","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma to soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":true},{"option":"Damage to blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding disorders","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 6-year-old boy came with his mother to the outpatient department with a complaint of nasal obstruction, nasal discharge with bedwetting at night. On examination, the boy had an open mouth and, a pinched nose with prominent incisors. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hemangioma","bool":false},{"option":"Antrochoanal polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Choanal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoids","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic tonsillitis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 35-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of a combination of fluctuating sensorineural hearing loss, roaring tinnitus, episodic vertigo, and fullness of the ear. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Meniere's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Perilymph fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic suppurative otitis media","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 23-year-old male comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of nasal obstruction and pain in the nose. On examination, he has bilateral septal swelling which is very tender to touch. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Deviated nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Neoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Acute rhinosinusitis","bool":false},{"option":"Septal abscess","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 28-year-old male patient was diagnosed with a case of nasopharyngeal carcinoma (stage III). What is the best treatment option for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Surgery followed by chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Radiotherapy","bool":true},{"option":"Surgery followed by radiotherapy","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 67-year-old female patient has been diagnosed with a case of malignant otitis externa. What is the common causative microorganism involved in this pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Aspergillosis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes virus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteroides","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 16-year-old boy presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of severe earache with bleeding from the ear. On otoscopy, the tympanic membrane has hemorrhagic bullae. He also has a history of upper respiratory infection. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster oticus","bool":false},{"option":"Ramsay Hunt syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Bullous myringitis","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 25-year-old healthy female patient presents to the ENT outpatient department with a complaint of progressively increasing midline swelling of the neck for 1 year. On examination, it moves on to swallowing. What is the most suitable non-invasive radiological investigation for the diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"Plain x-ray of neck","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":true},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"In a patient with acute otitis media, which of the following best describes the primary pathophysiological mechanism leading to the development of middle ear inflammation and effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Allergic reaction in the middle ear","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive wax accumulation","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired cerumen production","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube dysfunction","bool":true},{"option":"Dysfunction of the vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"An industrialist asks for advice from a public health specialist about the best measures he can take to control noise in the generator factory that he is going to set up. The public health specialist recommends noise control measures at the workplace. Which of the following is the highest measure for control of hazards at the workplace according to the hierarchy of controls?","answers":[{"option":"Personal protective equipment (PPE)","bool":false},{"option":"Substitution","bool":false},{"option":"Administrative controls","bool":false},{"option":"Engineering controls","bool":false},{"option":"Elimination","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 30-year-old male patient who had a history of left ear discharge for the past 5 years, now reported to the ENT clinic with the complaint of severe persistent headache, fever, and vomiting. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Subdural abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocephalus","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthitis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve paralysis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 24-year-old female presents to the clinic with a history of dysphagia to solids for the past 2  years. Her hemoglobin is 7.6 mg/dl. What will be the most likely finding on a barium swallow?","answers":[{"option":"Esophageal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Achalasia cardia","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal foreign body","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal web","bool":true}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 13-year-old  boy presents to the outpatient department with a history of profuse bleeding from his nose on and off, right-sided nasal blockage, and right-sided hearing impairment for the last 8 months. On anterior rhinoscopic examination, a pinkish mass is seen in the right nostril. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bleeding polyposis","bool":false},{"option":"Sinonasal polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharyngeal adenoids","bool":false},{"option":"Epistaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharyngeal angiofibroma","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"An 18-year-old female patient presents with a boil in the nose. What is the best method for examination of the nasal vestibule in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"By asking the patient to lower her head","bool":false},{"option":"By nasal endoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"By Thudichum's nasal speculum","bool":false},{"option":"By Killian's nasal speculum","bool":false},{"option":"By elevating tip of the nose with thumb","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"While performing a clinical examination of the nose in a 22-year-old female patient, palpation of the paranasal sinuses is done. Which of the following structures is not possible to palpate?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 35-year-old lady developed septal adhesion after septal surgery 6 months back. What measures should have been taken at that time to prevent such complications?","answers":[{"option":"Doing surgery under general anesthesia","bool":false},{"option":"Giving prophylactic antibiotic after surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Avoid nasal packing","bool":false},{"option":"Giving NSAID drugs post-operatively","bool":false},{"option":"Putting splints after surgery","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"Proof puncture or antral washout was planned in a 25-year-old male patient. Which of the following structures is drained in this operation?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A father brought his 5-year-old son with the complaint of rapidly progressing respiratory distress, stridor, dysphagia, and high-grade fever for the last day. Which of the following radiological investigations would be the most helpful for diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray neck (AP) view","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray chest (PA) view","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray nasopharyngeal lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray PNS Water's view","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray neck lateral view","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A lobectomy was planned for a 35-year-old woman who presented with a solitary thyroid nodule in the right lobe. Which of the following structures is at the most risk of damage during surgery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 38-year-old male patient was diagnosed with a case of salivary calculus. What is the most common site for calculus formation?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular gland and its duct","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Deep lobe of parotid","bool":false},{"option":"Minor salivary gand","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial lobe of parotid gland and its duct","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male was diagnosed with a malignant tumor of the oral cavity. Which of the following is the most common malignant tumor of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Mucoepidermoid carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoid cystic carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"During a careful examination of a patient's ear, a physician identifies a distinct bulge on the medial wall of the middle ear. This elevation results from which of the underlying structures?","answers":[{"option":"Basal turn of cochlea","bool":true},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Stapes","bool":false},{"option":"Round window","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular promontory","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 32-year-old patient presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of hearing loss and facial weakness on the left side. Imaging studies revealed a lesion in the internal acoustic meatus. Which of the following cranial nerves is commonly found in the internal acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Cranial nerve VII and VIII","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve IX and X","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve III and IV","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve V and VI","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve XI and XII","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A patient presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of hearing loss and difficulty in distinguishing between different pitches of sound. During an audiometric evaluation, the audiologist identified a dysfunction related to the organ responsible for hearing, present on the basilar membrane. What is the name of this organ?","answers":[{"option":"Organ of Corti","bool":true},{"option":"Organ of weber","bool":false},{"option":"Organ of helicotrema","bool":false},{"option":"Organ of eustachian","bool":false},{"option":"Organ of rinne","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 45-year-old traffic policeman visited a family physician and complained of traffic noise during his duty at Shahreh-e-Faisal. He further explained that he applied for a transfer to an office job but his application was denied. He sought advice from the physician on how to avoid this annoyance. Which one of the following options is the most appropriate and practical advice that the doctor must give to the traffic warden?","answers":[{"option":"Stay in office","bool":false},{"option":"Plant a barrier from the traffic","bool":false},{"option":"Evade honking by giving chalan","bool":false},{"option":"Change job","bool":false},{"option":"Use personal protective equipment (PPE)","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A student selected a group of poor patients from Civil Hospital, Karachi. He intended to generalize the results of his study on the population of the Karachi city. Which of the following biases will distort the results of his research study?","answers":[{"option":"Information bias","bool":false},{"option":"Observer bias","bool":false},{"option":"Selection bias","bool":true},{"option":"Recall bias","bool":false},{"option":"Misclassification bias","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A group of students intended to control the unwanted effects of an extraneous factor in their observational study design. Which of the following methods will help them to control this extraneous factor?","answers":[{"option":"Placebo control group","bool":false},{"option":"Double-blind design","bool":false},{"option":"Triple-blind design","bool":false},{"option":"Random assignment","bool":false},{"option":"Age-matched participants","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A researcher wants to provide everybody a chance to be included in the research study. What is the best method to select participants?","answers":[{"option":"Multivariate analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Randomization","bool":true},{"option":"Stratification","bool":false},{"option":"Blinding","bool":false},{"option":"Restriction","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/ent/2023","question":"A 3-year-old child presents in the outpatient department with complaints of nasal obstruction, snoring, and prominent upper teeth. A differential diagnosis of adenoids is established. What is the best investigation for this case?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray nasopharynx soft tissue lateral view","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior rhinoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"Rigid nasopharyngoscopy under sedation","bool":false},{"option":"Ct scan nose and paranasal sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"Flexible nasopharyngoscopy under local anesthesia","bool":false}]}]
export default arr